Inventory of the Cassimere Churchill Papers 1862-
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Cassimere Churchill Papers 1862
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2008.42
0.10
24 items
Letters from Cassimere Churchill, a member of Company E, 9th Cavalry Regiment, New York, to his family while stationed in New York, Washington, D.C. and Virginia during the Civil War. A participant in the battles of Yorktown, Va. and Williamsburg, Va. as an artillery guard; descriptions of Yorktown, Va., Manassas, Va. and Washington, D.C. Includes descriptions of camp life, surrounding area, as well as his opinions of the war and the Union's leadership.
Churchill, Cassimere, 1840-1861 arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 00/00/2008.
Biographical Note
Cassimere Churchill was born on October 20, 1840 in Alexander, Genesee Co., New York to Cullen Dyer and Caroline Brown Churchill. He enlisted in Company E, 9th Cavalry Regiment New York on December 7, 1861. He died on September 3, 1862 as result of a wound inflicted in Alexandria, Virginia. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Cassimere Churchill.
Scope and Contents
Letters from Cassimere Churchill, a member of Company E, 9th Cavalry Regiment, New York, to his family while stationed in New York, Washington, D.C. and Virginia during the Civil War. A participant in the battles of Yorktown, Va. and Williamsburg, Va. as an artillery guard; descriptions of Yorktown, Va., Manassas, Va. and Washington, D.C. Includes descriptions of camp life, surrounding area, as well as his opinions of the war and the Union's leadership.
Arrangement of Materials
Chronological.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence
Geographic Name:
Virginia--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
Topical Term:
United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Williamsburg (Va.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Yorktown (Va.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Letters from Cassimere Churchill to his family, 1862; id26015
  - November 18, 1861 to December 1861, id26019 (Folder 1)
    - November 18, 1861, id26017 (Folder 1)
    - December 10-16, 1861, id26020 (Folder 1)
    - December 18, 1861, id26021 (Folder 1)
    - December 24, 1861, id26022 (Folder 1)
    - January 1, 1862, id26023 (Folder 1)
    - January 4-5, 1862, id26024 (Folder 1)
    - January 10-16, 1862, id26025 (Folder 1)
    - January 18, 1862, id26026 (Folder 1)
    - January 18-February 3, 1962, id26027 (Folder 1)
  - February 1862 - July 15, 1862, id26018 (Folder 2)
    - February 3, 1862, id26028 (Folder 2)
    - February 16-28, 1862, id26036 (Folder 2)
    - February 18, 1862, id26047 (Folder 2)
    - March 6 (1862), id26048 (Folder 2)
    - March 11-19 (1862), id26049 (Folder 2)
    - March 19, 1962, id26050 (Folder 2)
    - April 7, 1862, id26051 (Folder 2)
    - April 8 - May 3, id26052 (Folder 2)
    - April 22, 1862, id26053 (Folder 2)
    - June 2, 1862, id26054 (Folder 2)
    - June 12, 1862, id26055 (Folder 2)
    - June 14, 1862, id26056 (Folder 2)
    - June 17, 1862, id26057 (Folder 2)
    - July 15, 1862, id26058 (Folder 2)
- Letter from C.D. Churchill to a Son, (1862); id26016